# Josh Mills

millsaj@pm.me • (587) 830 5452 • Based in Canmore, Alberta

#### Introduction

For 8 years I have been a software developer, working in an office or at home on a computer. Last year I moved to Canmore to facilitate a more active lifestyle and am now looking to be able to work with people face to face and be more part of my local community.

I currently have a two year open work visa and am applying for permanent residency. I live up near Quarry Lake and should easily be able to commute by foot or bike.

I have experience working in and leading teams, working under pressure to a high quality and interacting with business-to-business customers.

# Experience

## Appt Health

#### Lead Developer

London, United Kingdom July 2020 - April 2024

Appt Health helps the NHS provide preventative healthcare by automating the call and recall process for patients.

Working as the Lead Developer at a startup in the healthcare space required the ability to work fast under pressure whilst maintaining the level of quality required when dealing with clinical risk.

I led and managed a small team of other developers; doing so was an exciting challenge that has made me a better team player.

It was my responsibility to set our development standards, encourage and train other developers, manage our weekly goals, have the final say on major decisions and evaluate new technical hires.

#### The Day News & Media

LONDON, UNITED KINGDOM

July 2018 – June 2020

# Full Stack Developer

The Day is a news website for school children between 9 and 16 years old. They create newspaper-like resources to be used in class to improve news literacy and motivation for learning.

For most of my time here I was the only developer, working with the wider team of journalists and customer support staff. I enjoyed my time here but untimately wanted more interaction with other developers.

#### Nublue

Lancaster, United Kingdom

## PHP Developer

October 2015 – January 2018

Nublue is a web development agency, for which I worked on a number of ecommerce sites.

This was my first development role and was part time whilst I studied at university. The work was dynamic - requiring me to fill in across several teams as required on a weekly basis. It taught me how to be flexible and responsive to the current needs of a business.

#### Falcon Workshop Supplies

Wigan, United Kingdom

# Warehouse Packer & Sales Assistant

2011 - 2014

Falcon Workshop Supplies operated mostly as a EBay store selling supplies for woodworking.

I was mostly responsible for packaging orders for delivery. We also had some walk in clients so I also served some customers that came to the warehouse directly.

#### Skills and interests

**Workplace Skills:** Good team player with some leadership experience. Self motivated and hard working. Friendly and outgoing. Open attitude to criticism and improvement.

Interests: Reading, hiking, climbing, video games and good tea.

#### **Education**

#### Lancaster University

LANCASTER, UNITED KINGDOM

# **MSci Hons Computer Science**

2014 - 201

I graduated with a masters in computer science. I enjoyed my time at university: I participated in some charity work for amnesty international as well as a small work placement at a local resilience forum in Lancaster that helped facilitate the response to local emergencies.